A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Special Collections, Grant Funded Materials FA1839
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grant File Attachments - Publications and Reports, 1955-2018; 5; 23.46 Cubic Feet
  - Educational Forum (10251671) - Contacto Educativo: El Programa Para Forjar el Cambio, 2003; CD (Box 52)
  - Educational Forum (10251671) - Alerta Educativa: Sintesis Noticiosa, 2001-2003; CD (Box 52)
  - Foundation-Administered Project (10190003) - Pacific Data, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 280)
  - Foundation-Administered Project (10190003) - Armnet, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 281)
  - EngenderHealth (10251720) - Reports, 2005 (Box 53, Folder 282)
    Grantee: EngenderHealth
    Grant Dates: 2002 July 01-2005 June 30
    Grant Number: 10251720
    Grant Purpose: For training and technical assistance to South African NGOs with respect to educating young men about HIV/AIDS and gender relationships
    Ford Program Officer(s): Okedi, William; Floyd, Virginia Davis; TBS/Sexuality & Reproductive Health; Brown, Alice L.
  - Regents of the University of Michigan (10300349) - Project on Can Civil Society Moderate Ethnic Conflict? A Multi-Country Study, Ashutosh Varshney, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 283)
    Grantee: Regents of the University of Michigan
    Grant Dates: 2003 January 01-2005 December 31
    Grant Number: 10300349
    Grant Purpose: $425,000.00; $425,000.00
    Grant Amount: For research on the impact of inter-ethnic networks of civic engagement on incidence of conflict
    Ford Program Officer(s): Edwards, Michael; Raman, Sushma; TBS/PSJ
  - National Association of Black Journalists (09701349) - Conventions, 1999-2000 (Box 53, Folder 284)
    Grantee: National Association of Black Journalists
    Grant Dates: 1997 August 01-2004 July 31
    Grant Number: 09701349
    Grant Purpose: Support for collaborative activities by minority journalists' associations to promote improved diversity in the news media (950-1238)
    Grant Amount: $710,000.00; $710,000.00
  - International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources (IUCN) (10101847), 2004 (Box 53, Folder 285)
    Grantee: International Union for Conservation of Nature and Natural Resources (IUCN)
    Grant Dates: 2001 July 01-2003 June 30
    Grant Number: 10101847
    Grant Purpose: General support for IUCN Mozambique's integrated environment and natural resources management program and to develop a forest products certification program
    Ford Program Officer(s): Murombedzi, James C.
  - The Finance Project Toward Improved Methods of Financing Education and Other Children's Services, Inc. (09700947), 1997-1998 (Box 53, Folder 286)
    Grantee: The Finance Project
    Grant Dates: 1997 June 01-2005 May 31
    Grant Number: 09700947
    Grant Purpose: Continued partial support for the welfare information network for state and local policy makers and officials (960-1149)
    Grant Amount: $1,050,000.00; $1,050,000.00
  - Fairness Accuracy in Reporting Inc. (FAIR) (09701345), 1999 (Box 54, Folder 287)
    Grantee: Fairness Accuracy in Reporting Inc.
    Grant Dates: 1997 July 01-2004 April 30
    Grant Number: 09701345
    Grant Purpose: General support to monitor and analyze the performance of the news media in the United States
  - Fairness Accuracy in Reporting Inc. (FAIR) (09701345) - Nancy Zirkin on Title IX; Peter Sussman on Media and Prisons; Hosts: Janine Jackson and Peter Hart, Produced by FAIR CounterSpin, 1999 April 23-30; inch audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15897)
    Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact a RAC archivist for further instruction.
  - Fairness Accuracy in Reporting Inc. (FAIR) (09701345) - Alex Cockburn on "Chinese Spying;" Hosts: Janine Jackson and Steve Rendall, Produced by FAIR CounterSpin, 1999 March 19-26; inch audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15898)
  - Fairness Accuracy in Reporting Inc. (FAIR) (09701345) - Barbara Miner on Vouchers; Dean Baker on ERR; Hosts: Janine Jackson and Steve Rendall, Produced by FAIR CounterSpin, 1999 May 14-21; inch audio cassette (Box 1, Tape AV 15899)
  - World Association of Community Radio Broadcasters (10401231) - AMARC InterRadio and AMARC-Link Publications, 2004-2005 (Box 54, Folder 288)
    Grantee: World Association of Community Radio Broadcasters
    Grant Dates: 2004 August 01-2005 April 30
    Grant Number: 10401231
    Grant Purpose: General support to defend and promote freedom of expression by building policy expertise and capacity for community media worldwide
    Grant Amount: $235,000.00; $235,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Lentz, Roberta G.; Aguirre, Mariano A.; Toni, Ana; Abreg, Martn; Siskel, Suzanne E.; Gitari, Joseph
  - The Regents of the University of California, Santa Cruz (10100530) - Social Change Across Borders, 1998-2002 (Box 54, Folder 289)
    Grantee: The Regents of the University of California, Santa Cruz
    Grant Dates: 2001 March 01-2003 February 28
    Grant Number: 10100530
    Grant Purpose: Partial support to strengthen the University's Social Change Across Borders summer institutes and to establish a transnational learning network
    Ford Program Officer(s): Duncan, Cynthia M.
  - The Regents of the University of California, Santa Cruz (10100530) - Summer Institute Social Change Across Borders Video, undated; VHS (Box 1, Tape AV 11196)
  - National Security Archive Fund (10050224), 2000 (Box 54, Folder 290)
    Grantee: National Security Archive Fund
    Grant Dates: 1999 October 01-2001 September 30
    Grant Number: 10050224
    Grant Purpose: To sustain and expand the archives's project of historical recovery and internation accountable concerning Chile
    Grant Amount: $167,000.00; $167,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Abreg, Martn
  - Pinchot Institute (10002020) - The Pinchot Letter, 2001 (Box 54, Folder 291)
    Grantee: Pinchot Institute
    Grant Dates: 2000 March 01-2004 February 29
    Grant Number: 10002020
    Grant Purpose: Support for research, policy analysis, and meetings on sustainable community forestry in the united states
    Grant Amount: $400,000.00; $400,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Campbell, J. Y. (Jeffrey Y.)
  - Arkansas Advocates for Children and Families (10101630), 2002 (Box 55, Folder 292)
    Grantee: Arkansas Advocates for Children and Families
    Grant Number: 10101630
    Grant Purpose: For activities to increase state commitment to working poor families in Arkansas
    Grant Amount: $325,000.00; $325,000.00
  - Parish Of Trinity Church (07450391) - The Next Step: Towards Equality of Public Service, 1975 (Box 55, Folder 293)
    Report of the Conference on Public Service, Equalization Litigation, May 16-17, 1974, Trinity Parish, New York City, Sponsored Jointly by the Ford Foundation, The Irwin-Sweeney-Miller Foundation, and Trinity Parish
    Grantee: Parish Of Trinity Church
    Grant Dates: 1974 May 01-1974 October 30
    Grant Number: 07450391
    Grant Purpose: Partial support for the conference on public service equalization litigation
    Grant Amount: $3,000.00; $3,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Kelly, James A.
  - The University of the West Indies (07100179) Proceedings: Ninth West Indian Agricultural Economics Conference, 1974 (Box 55, Folder 294)
    Grantee: The University of the West Indies (),
    Grant Dates: 1971 March 17-1983 December 31
    Grant Number: 07100179
    Grant Purpose: Research in agricultural economics
    Grant Amount: $354,000.00; $354,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Collins, Norman R.; Puryear, Jeffrey
  - Government of East Pakistan (06200236) - An Evaluation of the Rural Public Works Programme, East Pakistan, 1962-1963, Pakistan Academy for Rural Development, 1963 October (Box 55, Folder 295)
    Grantee: Government of East Pakistan
    Grant Dates: 1962 April 18-1967 March 31
    Grant Number: 06200236
    Grant Purpose: Pilot Program of Cooperative Agricultural Development
    Grant Amount: $810,000.00; $810,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Rudlin, Walter A.
  - The Trustees of Columbia University in the City of New York (06200200) - Field Survey of Federal Pretrial Discovery: Report to the Advisory Committee on Rules of Civil Procedure, 1964 November (Box 55, Folder 296)
    Grant Dates: 1962 April 06-1964 April 05
    Grant Number: 06200200
    Grant Purpose: Study of the effect of the discovery process in civil law suits
    Ford Program Officer(s): 1962 April 06-1964 April 05
  - 73-3 Report to The Ford Foundation by John Paddock, Travel and Study Award 1973-1974, 1974 June 30 (Box 56, Folder 297)
  - Vanderbilt University (06100379) - Staff Study No. 2; Analysis of Instructional Programs in Fall Quarter or Semester, 1961, George Peabody College for Teachers and Vanderbilt University, Peabody-Vanderbilt Study of Possible Closer Cooperation, 1962 February (Box 56, Folder 298)
    Grantee: Vanderbilt University
    Grant Dates: 1961 October 05-1962 October 04
    Grant Number: 06100379
    Grant Purpose: Study of possible cooperation between Vanderbilt and George Peabody College
  - Vanderbilt University (06100379) - Staff Study No. 3: Historical Analysis of Cooperation Between George Peabody College for Teachers and Vanderbilt University, Peabody-Vanderbilt Study of Possible Closer Cooperation, 1962 May (Box 56, Folder 299)
  - American Academy of Arts And Sciences (06900110) - Plenary Sessions of the Conference on Negro Colleges, Sponsored by Daedalus, Journal of the American Academy of Arts And Sciences and Ford Foundation, House of the Academy, Boston, Massachusetts, 1969 March 6-7 (Box 56, Folder 300)
    Grantee: American Academy of Arts And Sciences
    Grant Dates: 1968 December 01-1971 June 30
    Grant Number: 06900110
    Grant Purpose: "Support for the preparation and publication of a series of papers on the governance of predominantly Negro colleges"
    Grant Amount: $63,000.00; $63,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Scanlon, John J.
  - American Academy of Arts And Sciences (06700191) - Plenary Sessions of the Conference on Adolescence: The Ages of 12-16, Sponsored by Daedalus, Journal of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and The Ford Foundation, House of the Academy, Boston, Massachusetts, 1969 April 17 (Box 56, Folder 301)
    Grant Purpose: Support for the preparation and publication of a series of papers on the governance of predominantly negro colleges
  - American Academy of Arts And Sciences (06700191) - Plenary Sessions of the Conference on Transforming Conceptions of Modern Science Sponsored by Daedalus Journal of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences and The Ford Foundation, Villa Serbelloni, Bellagio, Italy, 1969 September 10-14 (Box 57, Folder 302)
  - 69-673 Challenges in Higher Education Administration: Readings and Cases, Vol. 2, M. K. Subramaniam and M. Joseph, A Publication by Seminar of Registrars and Administrative Officers, undated (Box 57, Folder 303)
  - Trustees of Boston University (07000302) - Afro-American Studies Program, Occasional Paper Number One: American Law and The Black Community: Viewed by Black Women Lawyers, 1970 (Box 57, Folder 304)
    Grantee: Trustees of Boston University
    Grant Dates: 1970 May 20-1980 June 30
    Grant Number: 07000302
    Grant Purpose: Support for a graduate program in African American Studies
    Grant Amount: $467,158.00; $467,158.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Coolen, Marion A.; Payton, Benjamin Franklin
  - 73-412/Foundation-Administered Project (FAP) (06890734): Research And Planning On Secondary Education In India - Maharashtra Action Research Project in Occupational Education and Training, 1969 September 21-27 (Box 57, Folder 305)
    Grant Dates: 1968 September 01-1973 August 31
    Grant Number: 06890734
    Grant Purpose: Research And Planning On Secondary Education In India
    Grant Amount: $261,000.00; $245,250.68
    Ford Program Officer(s): Frodin, Reuben; Sommer, John G.
  - National Academy of Education (07200152) - Report and Working Papers, The Committee on Anthropology and Education, 1977 (Box 58, Folder 306)
    Grantee: National Academy of Education
    Grant Dates: 1972 February 01-1979 May 31
    Grant Number: 07200152
    Grant Purpose: Support to establish committees of scholars on anthropology and education, and on the economics and financing of education
    Grant Amount: $57,500.00; $57,500.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Kelly, James A.; Lynch, Barbara D.; Saario, Terry
  - The Council Of State Governments (06700190) - Preliminary Report of the Governors' Committee on Constitutional Revision and Governmental Reorganization, 1967 (Box 58, Folder 307)
    Grantee: The Council Of State Governments
    Grant Dates: 1967 April 07-1968 April 06
    Grant Number: 06700190
    Grant Purpose: Research and reporting of two subcommittees of the national governors' conference in preparation for the annual conference, oct 1967
    Grant Amount: $49,500.00; $49,193.25
    Ford Program Officer(s): Watts, William
  - Manpower Demonstration Research Corp (MDRC) PA 09800884 - Press Clippings and Research Design for an Evaluation of Project GRAD, 1998-2000 (Box 58, Folder 308, Box 59, Folder 309)
  - Hamilton College PA 10401086, 2005-2006 (Box 59, Folder 310)
    Grantee: Hamilton College
    Grant Dates: 2004 July 01-2008 August 31
    Grant Number: 10401086
    Grant Purpose: To develop an ethical model for creating a genuinely pluralist American public culture
    Grant Amount: $500,000.00; $500,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Richards, Elizabeth Theobald; Buchanan, Constance H.
  - UNESCO - IMC PA Photos PA 09900697, 2004; CD-R (Box 59)
    Grantee: University of Pittsburgh
    Grant Dates: 1999 April 01-2006 July 31
    Grant Number: 09900697
    Grant Purpose: Support to establish an international jazz institute and to collaborate with the University of Ghana
    Ford Program Officer(s): Pwono, Damien M.; Wilkerson, Margaret B. (Margaret Buford)
  - Rural Development Leadership Network (New York, NY) PA 10550886, 2005-2006 (Box 59, Folder 311)
    Grantee: Rural Development Leadership Network, Inc.
    Grant Dates: 2005 May 01-2007 May 31
    Grant Number: 10550886
    Grant Purpose: For the Mobilizing the Network project to reshape the organization into a more effective and visible vehicle for the promotion of sustainable and equitable development in rural communities
    Ford Program Officer(s): Gilbert, Linetta
  - Mexican Commission for the Defense and Promotion of Human Rights (Mexico) PA 10550986, 2005-2006 (Box 59, Folder 312)
    Grantee: Mexican Commission for the Defense and Promotion of Human Rights
    Grant Dates: 2005 August 01-2006 July 31
    Grant Purpose: To produce accurate and meaningful information regarding feminicide in Mexico and Guatemala and disseminate it at international forums
    Grant Amount: $60,000.00; $60,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Bronfman, Mario
  - National Congress of American Indians (NCAI) PA 10100396, 2003-2005 (Box 59, Folder 313)
    Grantee: NCAI Fund
    Grant Dates: 2001 January 01-2008 September 30
    Grant Number: 10100396
    Grant Purpose: Support for public education, outreach, and analysis on Native American issues by a national policy center
    Grant Amount: $1,025,000.00; $1,025,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Jenkins, Alan; Rios, Sara; Cox, Todd
  - Jubilee South Activities PA 10300352, 2003-2004 (Box 59, Folder 314)
    Grantee: Jubilee South, Incorporated
    Grant Dates: 2003 January 01-2006 December 31
    Grant Number: 10300352
    Grant Purpose: For research, education and network building on the debt burden of developing countries
    Ford Program Officer(s): Montes, Manuel F.; Jordan, Lisa
  - The John E. Fetzer Institute, Inc. - Action Research and Documentation Project Institute for Social Studies and Action PA 09000188, 2005 (Box 59, Folder 315)
    A Study of NGO and PO Programs and Projects on Reproductive Health and Rights Related to the Implementation of the ICPD Program of Action and the FWCW Platform for Action, 1994-2004
    Grantee: Institute for Social Studies and Action, Inc.
    Grant Dates: 1989 November 01-2005 June 30
    Grant Number: 09000188
    Grant Purpose: Support for the promotion and protection of women's reproductive health and rights in the Philippines
    Grant Amount: $1,082,000.00; $1,082,000.00
  - National Women's Law Center PA 10000985 - Articles, 2003-2006 (Box 60, Folder 316)
    Grantee: National Women's Law Center
    Grant Dates: 2000 April 01-2010 February 28
    Grant Number: 10000985
    Grant Purpose: Support for advocacy, policy and legal research, and related activities associated with the advancement of women, focusing on issues of child care and reproductive rights
    Grant Amount: $600,000.00; $600,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Neuborne, Helen; Lennon, Chauncy; Wadia, Anna
  - Film Arts Foundation (10400706) - Divided We Sprawl, CD: Production Materials, Torrice Productions, 2004-2006; CD-R (Box 60)
    Grantee: Film Arts Foundation
    Grant Dates: 2004 April 01-2006 February 28
    Grant Number: 10400706
    Grant Purpose: To produce and develop a community outreach plan for The New Metropolis, a public television documentary about sustainable metropolitan communities
    Ford Program Officer(s): Bagwell, Orlando; Anthony, Carl
  - The Institute for the Study of Islamic Thought in Africa (ISITA) PA 10100350 - Exploring the Islamic Intellectual Tradition in Africa, Summary Report of Activites for the period 1 January 2001 30 June 2002, 2002 October (Box 60, Folder 317)
    Grantee: Northwestern University
    Grant Dates: 2001 January 01-2012 February 29
    Grant Number: 10100350
    Grant Purpose: Support to establish an Institute for the Study of Islamic Thought in Africa
    Grant Amount: $2,024,000.00; $2,024,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Buchanan, Constance H.; Davaney, Sheila Greeve
  - Women's Edge Coalition (09801686) Coalition for Women's Economic Development and Global Equality, 1998-2007 (Box 60, Folder 318-319)
    Grantee: Womens Edge Coalition
    Grant Dates: 1998 July 01-2008 January 31
    Grant Number: 09801686
    Grant Purpose: Support for a coalition building and public education project on gender, aid, trade and development
    Grant Amount: $1,365,000.00; $1,365,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): BMontes, Manuel F.; Phillips, Barbara; Jordan, Lisa; Jenkins, Bonnie D.; Burlamaqui, Leonardo
  - GLIPLI FAP PA 989-1307 Moscow Office, Many Roads to Justice Correspondence, 2002 (Box 60, Folder 320)
  - Working Films, Inc PA 10550686, 2005 (Box 60, Folder 321)
    Grantee: Working Films
    Grant Dates: 2005 May 01-2006 April 30
    Grant Number: 10550686
    Grant Purpose: For a multitiered outreach and education campaign for the film "Two Towns of Jasper," designed to initiate discussion about bridging racial differences
    Ford Program Officer(s): Funabiki, Jon; Rios, Sara
  - Irvin M. Henderson Co. (Henderson, North Carolina) PA 10551156, 2006-2007 (Box 61, Folder 322)
    Grantee: Irvin M. Henderson Co.
    Grant Dates: 2005 August 15-2006 February 14
    Grant Number: 10551156
    Grant Purpose: To convene a diverse set of community advocates to discuss the recent changes within the financial services industry and the role of advocacy in improving access to financial services
    Ford Program Officer(s): McHale, Brandee
  - Save the Children Federation, Inc, Westport, Connecticut PA 10101600, 2001-2006 (Box 61, Folder 323)
    Grantee: Save the Children Federation
    Grant Dates: 2001 October 01-2005 March 31
    Grant Number: 10101600
    Grant Purpose: For knowledge building and public education promoting leadership for social change and to enhance development opportunities for emerging leaders in four Middle East countries
    Grant Amount: $641,000.00; $641,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Lapp, Sharry; Kodmani-Darwish, Bassma
  - Radio Television News Directors Foundation PA 10650101, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 324)
    Grant Dates: 2005 November 01-2006 July 31
    Grant Number: 10650101
    Grant Purpose: To conduct a research survey of local TV news directors and the general public about news media practices in order to help electronic journalists understand and adapt to changes in their field
  - Foundation-Administered Project PA 10690001, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 325)
    Grant Dates: 2005 October 01-2009 September 30
    Grant Number: 10690001
    Grant Purpose: For research and knowledge building in the democracy field, focusing on voting rights and the emerging area of structural reform and explore ways to encourage strategic thinking within the field
    Grant Amount: $345,000.00; $345,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Williams, Thomasina
  - Foundation-Administered Project PA 10690002, 2006 (Box 61, Folder 326)
    Grant Dates: 2006 January 01-2007 December 31
    Grant Number: 10690002
    Grant Purpose: To develop communications strategies that increase dialogue and raise awareness about adolescent male reproductive health issues
    Grant Amount: $0.00; $0.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Harris, Loren
  - Winrock International Institute of Agricultural Development PA 10650200, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 327)
    Grantee: Winrock International Institute for Agricultural Development
    Grant Dates: 10650200
    Grant Number: 2005 December 01-2007 November 30
    Grant Purpose: To establish a natural resource products network to facilitate training, capacity building and coordination of producers and traders of natural resource products in Southern Africa
    Ford Program Officer(s): Nimpuno-Parente, Paula
  - Foundation for Interregional Projects PA 10650100, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 328)
    Grantee: Non-Profit Organization "Foundation for Interregional Projects"
    Grant Dates: 2005 October 01-2008 October 31
    Grant Number: 10650100
    Grant Purpose: For a partnership of regional art museums in central Russia to create projects on city identities and cultural landscapes
    Grant Amount: $278,000.00; $278,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Yurna, Irina
  - New York Lesbian and Gay Experimental Film Festival, Inc PA 10650102, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 329)
    Grantee: New York Lesbian and Gay Experimental Film Festival
    Grant Dates: 2005 October 01-2006 September 30
    Grant Number: 10650102
    Grant Purpose: To complete a series of interviews of ACT-UP New York City artists for an oral history archive
    Ford Program Officer(s): Winters, David; McGovern, Terry
  - Indigenous Council of Roraima PA 10650202, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 330)
    Grantee: Indigenous Council of Roraima
    Grant Dates: 2005 December 01-2006 November 30
    Grant Number: 10650202
    Grant Purpose: To provide legal assistance and training to indigenous peoples in the state of Roraima
    Ford Program Officer(s): Cox, Todd; Dora, Denise Dourado
  - Federal University of Rio de Janeiro PA 10650103, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 331)
    Grantee: Federal University of Rio de Janeiro
    Grant Dates: 2005 October 01-2009 December 31
    Grant Number: 10650103
    Grant Purpose: To foster a public and regular collaboration on forced labour studies among universities and civil society
    Ford Program Officer(s): Dora, Denise Dourado
  - Amazon Argo-Extractive Center PA 10650203, 2005 (Box 61, Folder 332)
    Grantee: Amazon Agro-Extractive Center
    Grant Number: 10650203
    Grant Purpose: For community-based, environmentally sound income-generating projects to improve the livelihoods of traditional peoples in the Amazon Deforestation Belt
    Grant Amount: $36,000.00; $36,000.00
    Ford Program Officer(s): Vianna, Aurelio
  - Yayasan Masyarakat Mandiri Film Indonesia PA 10301243 In-Docs Addendum, 2004 October (Box 61, Folder 333)
    Grantee: Yayasan Masyarakat Mandiri Film Indonesia
    Grant Dates: 2003 May 01-2012 March 31
    Grant Number: 10301243
    Grant Purpose: For screenings, discussions, and educational programs to promote documentary film in Indonesia
    Grant Amount: $1,077,556.00; $1,077,556.00